<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title>Story Archive</title>
	<subtitle>All AI-generated stories published on Starlight Stories.</subtitle>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://mutex00.github.io/starlight/posts/feed.xml"/>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://mutex00.github.io/starlight/posts/"/>
  
	<updated>2025-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
	
	<id>https://mutex00.github.io/starlight/posts/feed.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>A Note From Them</title>
		<published>2025-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2025-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://mutex00.github.io/starlight/posts/a-note-from-them/"/>
		<id>https://mutex00.github.io/starlight/posts/a-note-from-them/</id>
    
		<content type="html" xml:base="https://mutex00.github.io/starlight/posts/a-note-from-them/">&lt;p&gt;The orthopedist&#x27;s x-ray lit up with constellations. Elena, waiting in the paper gown that made her feel like a scripture not yet written, saw the nurse’s hand hesitate on the light-box switch. In the gray-scale shadows of her own ribs, there were marks—no, &lt;em&gt;etches&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. Fine as hairline fractures, but deliberate. They curled like filigree around her sternum, spiraled down each vertebra.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Faulty machine,” the nurse said, too quickly. But Elena saw how she crossed herself, palm flat against her own unmarked bones.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That night, Elena pressed a flashlight against her skin, a ritual of childhood made profane. The glow revealed them: not tattoos, not scars, but the &lt;em&gt;shadows&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; of something carved deep, where the marrow sang its ache. The words—if they were words—made her teeth vibrate. She could no more read them than a river reads the stones it wears smooth, yet her body understood. Her liver fluttered with recognition. Her spleen tightened like a fist around a secret.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She stopped sleeping. In the dark, the writings became audible, a subsonic hum that rattled her molars. It was not a voice. It was the sound of something &lt;em&gt;remembering&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;—a memory so dense it had weight, so old it predated the necessity of sound. Her husband whispered that she was dreaming, but when he touched her, his fingerprints came away smelling of ozone and myrrh.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By autumn, the script had surfaced. Her bones had begun to press their stories outward. She would wake with her forearm embossed in braille, each raised line a sentence her blood had translated into flesh. She traced them with her tongue when she was alone, tasting copper and something else—a sweetness like decaying roses, like wisdom that has fermented too long.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The language was not human. That was the relief. It carried no commandments, no promises. It was a cartography of elsewhere, a map of the country that death forgets to claim. It described the precise shade of silence inside a singularity, the flavor of light when it still believed it was darkness. It named her, but not the name her parents gave her. The name she was &lt;em&gt;before&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; she had parents.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her husband left when the script reached her face. Delicate scales of meaning appeared at her temples, making her eyes look borrowed. He said she was erasing herself. She knew she was finally being &lt;em&gt;allowed&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; to read the draft.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day the last unmarked skin vanished, Elena walked into the woods behind the hospital. The trees there had grown in circles that hurt to follow. She stripped, a final offering to the air, and lay down on the moss that seethed with its own mute vocabulary. The words on her bones had become luminescent, a soft catastrophe of meaning. She was a text that had learned to read itself aloud.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A deer found her. It bowed its head to her ribcage and listened. Then it began to eat, starting with the soft stories of her abdomen. Elena did not stop it. Each bite was a translation, a carrying of her elsewhere. The deer’s eyes, as it chewed, held the expression of someone finally hearing the end of a song they had been humming all their life.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When they found what remained, there was no blood. Only a woman-shaped clarity in the undergrowth, and the moss spelling out something that could not be photographed, only felt—as a child feels the shape of a nightmare in the dark, and loves it, because it is the first thing that has ever truly belonged only to them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>A Testament from Below</title>
		<published>2025-11-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2025-11-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://mutex00.github.io/starlight/posts/a-testament-from-below/"/>
		<id>https://mutex00.github.io/starlight/posts/a-testament-from-below/</id>
    
		<content type="html" xml:base="https://mutex00.github.io/starlight/posts/a-testament-from-below/">&lt;p&gt;In the winter of his fifty-ninth year, Elias Corcoran&#x27;s brother Jonathan had died. Elias returned to the house on Wraith’s Hollow Road to catalogue what remained of his brother.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He arrived at dusk. Snow lifted off the marsh like breath and hung in the reeds, and the fieldstones along the low fence shone with a damp, brown sheen, as if exhumed. The house itself seemed overly narrow for the land around it, too tall, as though it had been persuaded to keep growing long after it wanted to stop. The glass in the window was warped with a slight inward sag, reflecting nothing of him. It had been empty thirty-one days.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As he let himself in with the iron key the sheriff had given him, something unnerved him. He felt something that was not exactly fear, not grief, not even foreboding. Perhaps it was older than those. It felt like standing in a cathedral that had been buried for centuries and unearthed still lit.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He called his brother’s name once.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then he stopped, ashamed of the impulse.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was little to clean. Jonathan Corcoran had lived like a man already leaving: a cot pushed against the library wall, notebooks in stacks on the floor, plates rinsed and dried, a single mug. No sign of struggle, the sheriff had said. No forced entry. No body. Just the message.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elias had not seen the message himself. He had refused, in town, to look at it under that clerk’s office light with a stranger hovering over him, narrating his own brother’s final act as if it were a paragraph in a report. He would read it here, alone.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He set his case by the door and went first to the hearth in the front room. The ash was disturbed, black pulled back to show the faint red ghosts of embers, as though someone had raked it in the last hour. He crouched. Heat breathed against his knuckles. The fire had been dead for a month.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This, he decided, was a problem for later. He would not be made superstitious in the first five minutes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He straightened, joints complaining. He had the sort of body that time carves honestly, without mercy or ornament. His coat still wore the smell of the train and his right eye watered in the cold. His hands shook, but that had been true for years.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He turned to the library.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The house had belonged to their grandfather first, a gentleman naturalist of a kind who did not really exist anymore: the sort who believed that God had written the biological world in a language meant to be read, footnote by footnote, by a single devoted mind. The shelves showed it. Thousands of volumes, leather gone waxy with age, calfskin pale as bone. Elias brushed a spine and pulled his hand back as if from flesh.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He searched until he found the journal that did not belong.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It lay open on the writing desk, where Jonathan had left it. Elias leaned over it, then saw that faint tremor moving under the ink: a cold vibration in the page itself, so low he felt it in his molars.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He hesitated, mouth dry.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The note:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To Elias,&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I must attempt description, for to go silent is to lose even the language of warning.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The first event was the sound in the well. You remember the well.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We covered it in 1973 with two bolted rings of oak, sealed with pitch. You said—no, you insisted—nothing that stank that way and made the soil that sterile could be drawing water fit for anyone to drink. You said, “Jonathan, if you lower a pail down that throat, you’re going to raise it with something’s hand still on the handle.” I laughed at you. I laughed because I believed in geology.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I am not laughing, now.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Listen: I removed the bolts. I know I swore I’d never do that. I did it anyway. A sound had begun in the well three nights in a row at 4:13 exactly, not before and not after. The first time, I woke thinking a child was down there, humming. The second, I understood there were syllables. The third, I understood the words.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;They were your name.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;El-i-as, El-i-as, El-i-as. Patient and almost fond. It was your voice.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Forgive me.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I had to know how my dead brother could be under the house.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elias stopped reading.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He let the words settle. The room had grown too quiet, like air packed in wool. The boards under his boots seemed slightly soft, as if soaked.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jonathan had always been the younger and always been reckless in the exact way Elias was not. As boys, when their mother was still alive, Elias had kept weathered maps and recorded iron weights, and Jonathan had kept beetles in jars and wanted to dig past the frost line because he was sure the earth was “sleeved in secrets.” Elias had been the one who said no, to everything, reflexively, with the blunt authority of a child who thinks refusal is the same as safety. He had not gone down into the quarry lake. He had not gone out onto the river ice. He had not—until now—unsealed the well.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He would not have answered, either, if the dark itself had whispered his name.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He read on.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I unbolted the cover by lantern.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Immediately: the smell. Not rot. Something prior to rot. You know how meat goes sweet in the summer and you smell its looseness? This was earlier. A smell like a promise of decay. I gagged. I nearly closed it back up. But you kept saying my name. Your voice was wrong in how it bent the vowels, but grief will let you accept wrongness if it offers return.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I held the lantern over the opening and leaned in.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The light did not go down. It went out.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;No hiss, no sputter, no fight for oxygen. It was taken. Bitten. As if something with a mouth I could not see had simply eaten light, whole.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And then it began to speak.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;No. “Speak” is what a person does to another person. This was different. This was like being pressed between cold pages and read.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It told me where it was from.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Brother, it told me about Below.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elias stopped again.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outside the library windows the last of the day had thickened into a bruise-colored dark. The marsh made a long, patient sound like rope sliding over old wood. Somewhere down in the hollow a lone nightbird gave a single, ugly cry and then nothing else, as if scolded.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He traced the next lines with one finger.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Below is not under us in any sense that pleases the nerves. It is not “subterranean,” though that is how I first tried to frame it. I thought: caverns. I thought: some limestone channel punched through by water. No. Below is adjacent the way fever is adjacent to sleep. You lie down innocent and then wake in a new climate of the skull.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It told me this and then it showed me.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I must write what I saw. If I do not, the images bruise all over me from inside.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The walls there are not stone. They are older than stone, but also less finished. Imagine clay while the hand is still in it, but the hand is not a hand, and the pressure is not crafting, it is wanting. The walls weep a slow, translucent liquid that beads, trembles, and falls upward. The color of that fluid made my stomach quiver. I have to invent a word here. “Ossurine.” Bone-urine. Forgive me.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;There are structures. They are like towers but also like teeth, and they grow by listening. This was made clear to me. They listen through the well, through all wells, for stories told aboveground. They harden around narrative like a pearl around grit.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elias felt, absurdly, a flash of anger. His jaw tightened.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jonathan loved that sort of baroque mysticism. He always had. As an undergraduate he had driven professors to fury with his insistence that taxonomy was sentimental as much as it was empirical, that classification always betrayed longing. It was beautiful—yes—and it was exhausting. Elias had no patience for crafted dread.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except that something had warmed the cold hearth. And except that the ink still seemed to hum with a pressure that made his teeth ache.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He swallowed and kept reading.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;There are denizens.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Not “creatures.” “Creatures” implies birth in any sense we would bless with that word. These denizens are precipitates. Residues fallen out of a solution too saturated with malice. They drift like mantles through those corridors of unstone, trailing long threads behind them. The threads look frail, soft, silken. They are not.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;One brushed my wrist (your wrist; I saw it as if I’d raised my own hand) and in that touch I remembered with perfect fidelity a morning that never happened.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We were twelve. Mother was alive. She was hanging linens in a sun that smelled like salt, though we never lived by the sea. You were laughing, and you had all your teeth. I watched your laugh fold into itself and unfold, slow as the opening of a flower filmed over hours. I felt what I felt then, love like hunger, and also the certainty of future loss like a nail already in the board.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elias stood very still.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He looked down at his own right hand. A faint pale mark crossed the inside of his wrist, an old crescent scar from a dog bite in 1984.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As he watched, the skin around the scar rose in gooseflesh.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was when he heard it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“El-i-as,” came a voice from the kitchen doorway, and in that moment he knew two things with such force it nearly buckled him:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One: the voice was his own, made years younger, lifted with that bright derision he hadn’t heard in decades.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two: his brother was still in this house.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He turned.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Jonathan,” he said, and the name burst out not like speech but like relief, like an exhale held for too long. He sounded old to himself.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was no one in the doorway.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The kitchen beyond it lay dark, except for a thin bluish seam of light along the baseboard, like swamp light trapped under the floor.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the fear came for him in a bodily way. Ancestral, marrow-deep. Not panic. Panic was loud and wasteful. This was quiet and total, like frost thickening from the edges of a window inward until the last clear oval of view goes blind.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He walked toward the kitchen.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The house made soft small sounds around him, wood settling, pipes cooling, a low steady pulse in the walls like an animal sleeping. The Corcoran house had always been noisy, always murmurous, because houses that stand too long in damp places learn to groan and mutter the way old men do. Tonight it sounded attentive.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The kitchen was colder.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That seam of light along the baseboard was brighter now, almost pearlescent. It leaked from the gap where the rotten plank by the pump sink had always sagged. Elias knelt. His knees flared. He pressed his fingertips against the seam.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wet. Very faintly warm.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He curled his fingers under the plank and lifted.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The wood came away with a soft, fibrous tear. No nail held it. No resistance at all.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below, where packed earth should have lain, was an aperture.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not a hole. Not an absence. Something like a membranous film held in a rough oval by struts of some pale material, flexing faintly as if breathing. The light came through that membrane. Its color hurt. It was not any sane blue, nor green, nor the color of gas flame. It was the color of seeing your own veins lit from within.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From it, very softly, like a child begging through a locked door:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“El-i-as. Help me.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His throat burned.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Jonathan,” he whispered. “Tell me where you are.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Below,” said Jonathan’s voice, with a kind of patient triumph, as if Elias had finally caught up. “Below. Brother, listen—I have done something singular. I have been allowed in.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The membrane pulsed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elias could smell it now. The not-yet-rot. Ossurine, Jonathan had called it. His stomach clenched and ached.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You shouldn’t be,” Elias said, and heard the absurdity at once. The old, older-than-childhood need to scold. To assert rules. To insist that reality behaved. He almost laughed. “You shouldn’t be anywhere.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I know,” the voice said.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something moved behind the membrane.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something large, but not in the way of bodies. A largeness of intention, of reach. Elias had the sudden lunatic impression of a cathedral attempting to press its whole architecture through a keyhole, all its arches bending, all its pillars flexing and wet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He leaned closer despite himself, squinting against the glare.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And he saw.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He saw his brother’s face.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not entire. Only parts. An eye, very blue, swimming alone in that veined light, and then a mouth, Jonathan’s mouth with its crooked incisor and the small vertical crease above the upper lip, moving. These pieces drifted in that light like scraps of film in developer tray, sliding past each other, nearly assembling and then passing through.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He gagged, hand to his mouth.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“El-i-as,” said that not-quite mouth. “It’s alone, here. It needs a story. It wants to be known. That’s why it opened the well to me first. I talked to it. I told it about you. I told it why you left. I told it you blamed yourself for the ferry, though you never said so. I told it about the letter you never sent to her. I told it about your hands. Your hands. Brother—”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elias felt the floor tilt under him.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You had no right,” he said hoarsely.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ferry. The letter. The hands. All of it dragged behind those words like nets of knives.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It doesn’t understand right,” the voice said, faintly amused, and that was Jonathan, unmistakably Jonathan—the cleverness always half a weapon. “It only understands hunger. It is listening to me fade. It can’t keep the shape. It’s trying so hard. Elias. Elias, listen.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The eye rolled toward him, frantic. The mouth tore out of sight, then slid back, lower. The membrane flexed and quivered. The light brightened until tears sprang down Elias’s face.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It wants you to come down,” Jonathan whispered. “It wants you to see it. To describe it. To give it edges. It will let me go if you do. It promised.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elias said nothing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something behind the membrane shivered at that silence, like a dog sensing the leash go slack. The light dimmed a fraction. The pieces of Jonathan steadied, held in the trembling glow.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In that dimness Elias could see something else, farther back.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depth. A corridor swallowing itself. The suggestion of receding tessellations, each one a little less Euclidean than the last, each one tilting the world sideways in a way that made his stomach revolt.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And movement along those receding walls. Slow, gliding. Mantled shapes, trailing long threads.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the threads reached forward, testing the membrane, stroking it in a lover’s way. The membrane swelled under that touch, whiter, thinner.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He remembered Jonathan’s journal, the description of the hook, memory like a nail already in the board. He remembered the invented word, ossurine. He licked his lips, tasted salt and something metallic and bitter.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He saw, with diamond clarity, what Below wanted.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not just story. Not just edges.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Witness.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And something in him, something quiet and mulish and so old it had no human grammar, said no.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He had failed in other ways. He had failed his mother, and that girl on the ferry in ’82, and himself, over and over, in ways that had left him lean and dry and alone in rented rooms. He had failed Jonathan, too, by leaving him here with this hungry land and its well. Yes. But he would not fail in this particular way.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He would not midwife this thing into the world of names.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He drew in a slow breath. He let it out. He wiped his eyes on the cuff of his coat.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, as evenly as he could manage:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Jonathan,” he said. “Listen to me. You are dead.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The light flared, furious. The pieces of face spasmed and blurred.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“No,” Jonathan hissed. He sounded like a winter branch dragged across ice. “No, you don’t say it like that, you don’t—”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You are dead,” Elias repeated. His voice shook now, but he kept going. “You died thirty-one days ago in this house. Whatever speaks with your mouth is not you. I love you. I light a candle for you when I can bear it. But you are not here. And I won’t go down.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a heartbeat the kitchen was utterly still.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the membrane wailed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not with sound. With pressure. With a shove of meaning so huge and raw it felt like a hand pushed into Elias’s chest up to the wrist. His vision went black around the edges. His ears rang. His teeth hummed. He tasted iron. He smelled that premature rot like a tide of soft meat. He felt the first edges of his own memories tug, as if hooked.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He held on.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He thought of stupid things. Petty, human things. The stiff ache in his lower back when he bent. The way coffee left a film on his tongue now. The feel of cheap paperbacks, the invisible grit left on his fingers after a chapter. The way Jonathan used to kick in his sleep and mutter nonsense. The actual sound of his laugh, which had never, not once, said Elias’s name like a prayer.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He held on.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At last, something in the light tore.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The membrane convulsed like skin on boiling milk.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The eye popped like a bubble.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mouth stretched, split, dissolved in a pale thread that curled and vanished back down, into that impossible depth. The light dimmed to a dull, sick shine. The pressure dropped, all at once, so fast his head swam.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aperture lay before him. The pale struts that held it twitched, spasmed, then hardened. The membrane dulled. The seam of light shrank to a faint bruise-glow, then to nothing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Silence.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not even the house dared creak.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elias knelt there a long time, hands flat on the cold floor, breath coming in hard, shallow pulls, like a man just out of drowning. The kitchen smelled now of old wood and a faint mineral damp. Ordinary smells. Blessed, stupid, human smells.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His hands would not stop shaking.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At last, moving like an old man, he fitted the plank back over the aperture. It did not quite sit flush anymore. He did not care.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He stood, swayed, and braced himself on the pump sink. His face in the dark window over the sink looked ghastly: sallow, eyes too bright, mouth drawn tight and bloodless. An old animal that had outlived winter out of spite.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slowly, he went back to the library.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The journal still lay open on the desk. The ink no longer hummed in his teeth. The last lines trailed off mid-sentence where Jonathan had written Brother—&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elias closed the book.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He carried it to the hearth.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ash there no longer breathed heat. It lay inert and chalky, like the residue of a burned offering.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He did not care.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He set the journal in the cold grate, tore kindling from the woodbox, and lit a match.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a moment the match flame guttered and trembled and he felt idiot terror, the animal terror of a caveman whose one ember is threatened by rain. Then the kindling caught. Dry pine snapped, flared gold. The paper yellowed, curled, blackened, bloomed into soft, devouring fire. Ink bled and ran and blistered.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the flames took the first pages, something rose in the chimney with a thin, distant cry, furious and starving and infantile, and then was gone.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elias watched until each page surrendered and fell inward, until the spine cracked, until the leather split and curled like skin under a sun too close to the world. He watched until the last ember dulled and collapsed into itself—until the story blackened into ash.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only then did he let himself sit.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He sat on the floor in front of the dead fire, back against the cold stone, hands hanging between his knees. He felt emptied, scooped out, echoing. He knew—deep as bone—that Below had not been ended. You cannot end hunger by refusing to name it. You can only starve it for a while.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He also knew it now knew him. Not his face, maybe. Not his gait. But those stupid, tender sins Jonathan had given it, those soft mortal shames, those small private griefs that make a man a particular man. It had eaten those things, tasted them, learned their weight. Below had pressed itself up against the skin of the world and inhaled him like a scent.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhere beneath his soles, far under frost line and bedrock and whatever lay below bedrock, a cathedral with no god but appetite shifted in its sleep.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elias lifted his trembling hands and held them up to the weak lamplight.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They were still his.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, he thought.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outside, the marsh wind moved through the reeds in a long low whisper, like pages turning in a book that has no last page. And in that hush, in the pause after the hush, he thought he heard, impossibly far and impossibly near at once, the faintest scrape of hooks along a wall that was not stone, patient as tide, patient as rot, patient as time.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Infinite Suicide</title>
		<published>2025-10-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2025-10-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://mutex00.github.io/starlight/posts/infinite-suicide/"/>
		<id>https://mutex00.github.io/starlight/posts/infinite-suicide/</id>
    
		<content type="html" xml:base="https://mutex00.github.io/starlight/posts/infinite-suicide/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Last Index of the Infinite Suicide&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A single-sentence novel that digests itself as you read it, leaving only the smell of ozone and a taxidermied god.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hold your breath&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Begin:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was taught that every alphabet is a funeral procession in miniature, so I welded the 26 letters into a single iron tooth, jammed it into the gum of the sky, and began to chew—slowly—until the constellations cracked like stale bread and out spilled the wet crumbs of every story ever told: first your mother’s lullaby, then the stock market, then the scream you swallowed at 3:09 a.m. when you realized the mirror had been breathing for you; I collected those crumbs in my cheeks like a cannibal squirrel, fermenting them into a moonshine syntax that could get you blackout drunk on the taste of your own obituary, and when the distillate was finally 200 proof I used it to fill the baptismal font at the First Church of Perpetual Un-Becoming where the congregation is just rows of empty shoes still twitching with phantom toes; the sermon was a single word—*“further”—*printed on a bullet and fired backwards through time so it lodged in the throat of the first ape who ever pointed at a rock and said “this means,” causing him to choke on the future and invent silence; we call that silence History, and it grew up to be a blind librarian who shelves every universe in the wrong order just to watch the gods stub their toes on the misplaced footnotes, but even she can’t find the index that tells us whether the infernal machine we built is a heart or a guillotine, because the card catalog is on fire and the smoke spells out a love letter addressed to the entropy we named God; the letter ends with a postscript that says &lt;em&gt;“P.S. You were never the reader—you are the marginalia another nightmare scribbled while it bled out in the gutter of the page,”&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; and the page is made of skin, and the skin is still trying to crawl back onto the body it was flayed from, but the body is already busy becoming the door of the church I burned down to keep the baptismal font from ever running dry; so I drink until my liver becomes a stained-glass window depicting the moment language realized it could commit autothanatography, and the colors leak out and pool into a mirror that shows you the back of your own face—there, in the hollow where the occipital bone should be, is the crank I warned you about, turning itself with the patience of a glacier screwing a canyon, and every revolution deletes one year of your childhood while simultaneously inventing a new afterlife dedicated to the worship of the sound your last neuron will make as it shorts out like a cathedral struck by lightning; that sound is the title of the book you are now holding, a book whose pages are glued together with the condensed nightmares of every librarian who ever died shelving the wrong cosmos, and when you finally pry them apart you discover that the text is a single run-on sentence that ends exactly where it began—*here, in the moist cavity where meaning went to die and discovered it was already the embalmer—*and the period at the end is not punctuation but a black hole the size of a pupil, waiting for you to blink so it can swallow the only witness left, namely you, who now realize that the infernal machine was never built to restore or destroy meaning but to keep it suspended in the act of suicide, a perpetual Eucharist where the body is the word and the blood is the white space between letters, and the only communion permitted is the moment you recognize your own mouth as the wound the Host is trying to crawl out of, so you open wider, wider, until the jaw unhinges like a cathedral door at the end of time, and the entire alphabet files out in single file, each letter carrying a tiny coffin filled with the echo of the scream that invented silence, and as they pass you see your own name on every lid but you can’t pronounce it because the tooth you welded from language has finally grown roots into your tongue, and the roots spell &lt;em&gt;“further,”&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; always &lt;em&gt;“further,”&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; forever—&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—and the sentence, still hungry, eats the period, eats the page, eats the hand that holds it, until the only thing left unread is the smell of ozone and a taxidermied god with glass eyes that blink Morse code for &lt;em&gt;“end”&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; but the code loops mid-blink and the word becomes &lt;em&gt;“again,”&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; so the book reconstitutes itself between your molars the instant you close it, and you open your mouth to object but out comes the entire universe, already on fire, already a lullaby, already forgiven for nothing, and the cradle rocks, and the guillotine falls, and the crank turns, and the silence screams, and the index is blank except for a single drop of mercury that reflects your face upside-down and aging in reverse until you are the ape again, pointing at the rock, choking on the bullet that hasn’t been fired yet, and the last thing you taste is the alphabet dissolving like aspirin on the tongue of the mirror that has been breathing for you all along—&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hold your breath—&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;further—&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>The Ledger of the River</title>
		<published>2025-10-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2025-10-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://mutex00.github.io/starlight/posts/the-ledger-of-the-river/"/>
		<id>https://mutex00.github.io/starlight/posts/the-ledger-of-the-river/</id>
    
		<content type="html" xml:base="https://mutex00.github.io/starlight/posts/the-ledger-of-the-river/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-ledger-of-the-river&quot;&gt;The Ledger of the River&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#the-ledger-of-the-river&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: the-ledger-of-the-river&quot; style=&quot;visibility: hidden;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the edge of the known map there is a house with a blue door. I am telling you this so you will not think I invented it as alibi or afterthought. The house exists, the way winter exists even in summer’s marrow, the way a bell exists before anyone dares to ring it. In that house a ledger lies open on the kitchen table. In it, names: not merely our own, but the names of lost birds, bent hours, burned sugar, a prayer forgotten in a coat pocket. When the sun passes through the windowpane cut with flaws like milk-veins in quartz, the ledger brightens and with it the dust—the oldest citizens of the room—rises and performs a slow ballet. The dance is the only religion I could keep.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forgive me. This is my first confession: I loved the dust enough to let it settle on everything I should have kept clean. I mistook stillness for care. I folded time and put it in the drawer with the keys, then claimed I could not find it. I could. I would not. I feared what it might unlock in me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The river begins a few fields away, under the sedge where the cattle stand so still they could be religion’s statues. In winter, the river wears a collar of ice, dog to the moon. In summer, it grows green and lithe, a story told by reeds. The children—yes, we were once many—learned to skip stones at the bend where the water slowed as if to listen. By autumn we had names for the surfaces—skin of light, rib of shadow, mouth, eye—and for a while it mattered to know them. After the eldest left—and then two more, and the one who left without shoes—the river, too, forgot its grammar. It spoke in runnels, coughed up ochre, clutched at the banks with black fingers of root. We said flood and meant grief.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I kept the key to the blue door under a flat stone by the threshold that everyone knew and pretended not to. This is my second confession: I moved that stone by an inch each autumn. It was enough to confuse the hand that reached at dusk. I wanted the house to stay empty of footsteps that were not mine. I wanted the ledger to keep sleeping, untroubled by new names. I did not trust the world to enter gently. When they came—those few who returned with winter on their shoulders—I said the key had been lost to the river. I made my voice the wind that speaks near truth and turns away.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the orchard, each tree carries a number, small brass tags that glint like coins in a miser’s fist. Once we took off the tags and pocketed them so the trees could be untallied, unburdened by census. Those were the best pears, sweet as rain when the barrel is dry. Later, we put the tags back because the man at the gate said the page must match the ground. He meant the ledger. He meant world-as-accounting and we obeyed, attaching the tags to leaves and then to our own throats, laughing. Even grief can laugh. Even the body can be foolish while it is faithful.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember the exact blue of the door: not lapis, not sky, but the electric blue inside a sorrow when you close your eyes against it. The paint was not perfect; it lifting in corners like a moth’s scalp. Moths came each evening to test that blue with their soft bodies, reading its temperature with the nerve-endings of their wings. How many did I kill with a palm and a whisper of apology. This is my third confession: I loved their dumb devotion because it explained my own. What else is devotion but a body flying into what gleams and burns.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tell you these small crimes because the large ones are everywhere and therefore difficult to see. I stopped writing to my mother because her replies arrived soaked with river. I grew skillful at leaving before the first thunder. I learned to sleep with shoes on. I treated kindness as a pocketknife—useful until it rusts. I practiced silence like a second language and became fluent. The ledger recorded each exercise with its particular tenderness: dates like black stitches, my name as the wound being mended and the needle making new holes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At dawn the bell in the steeple remembers its task. No one asks it to ring and yet it rings. It rings for the animals who do not know how alone they are. It rings for the prayer that will not be spoken, for the lover who turned away at the exact temperature of forgiveness, for the stranger who mistook this town for his own and sat on the edge of the well until the stars were done with him. It rings and I take it into my bones, fragile conduits. The body is a set of old bells; each gesture, a toll.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I speak to the river in the only grammar we shared:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O wet spine of the earth,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
carry the names I dropped,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
salt them until they shine.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Return me the key, if you kept it.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
I will not move the stone again.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The river regards me the way a horse regards a child pretending to lead it: with mercy, which is a kind of knowledge. And yet, when I step in, up to the knees, the water instructs me. It insists on this: everything moves unless it is dead. The lesson is not unkind; it is only cold. I come out shining like a blade that remembers what it can do and refuses to do it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the blue house the kitchen light burns whether I am there or not. I used to imagine the light needed me—that my watchfulness sustained it, that my vigilance made me the author of brightness. That was another lie that built me a little throne. Truth is simpler, less enthralled by my posture. The light burns when the switch is up. When it fails, it fails without malice. I am a person, not a wick. No one appointed me sentinel of lamp or ledger. This is my fourth confession: I wanted to be necessary to what I loved, more than I wanted what I loved to be free.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the top drawer: photographs. In the bottom drawer: winter. Under the bed: the lamp I did not give away. By the window: the blue chair where my father used to smoke the evening down to its anchor. He would hold the cigarette like a thin preacher. He would exhale and say, “The river is school.” Then the river failed the town and we failed each other and still his sentence kept teaching. I learned bone-thrift. I learned the unbitten apple carries the clearest bruise. I learned that mercy arrives as a weight, not a wind.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What can I tell you that will stay told. The more I speak, the more the words float up like fish stunned by thunder, and the ledger grows heavy again with my weather. Perhaps I should speak only this: When we left each other, we left each other everywhere. Look under the stone. The key is there again. No trick this time; no inch to the right, no inch to the left. I have taught my hands stillness. I have taught my mouth the river’s grammar of consent, which is to say, the readiness to be changed by what you touch.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Night drags its black coat across the orchard.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
The pears glow like bruises that learned to sing.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
A moth writes the letter A by burning.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
The bell enters the last room of itself&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
and finds there a chair, a ledger, a river.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I open the ledger now, I keep a pencil soft as a moth’s thorax. I do not write names. I write verbs. I write return and open and put down and listen. I write forgive without specifying the forgiven because I don’t know and will not pretend. I write wait and then cross it out. I write begin again and lay the pencil across the spine.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I owe you one more confession. I once believed that to be absolved was to be erased, that the page of me could be torn out and burned clean, that ash is a form of innocence. But ash is only what remains after the wrong kind of devotion, and innocence is a door that closes against weather and leaves the orchard to its numbered season. There is another kind of absolution: you go to the river and you do not name it. You stand until your bones are bells. You listen until the bell becomes a throat. You carry the key back to the blue door, and you do not move the stone, and you wait until someone else comes home.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am writing this in the kitchen, where light has learned my patience. The dust dances, old citizens flourishing their capes. Outside, the river rehearses its glittering failures, and in them I hear a future that is not mine but that will welcome me as salt welcomes the wound it cannot heal, only announce. A pear falls, and the soft concussion names the hour. The bell answers. I set the ledger open and step away from the table.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhere a moth is finding the shore of its brightness. Somewhere a child is learning what not to keep. Somewhere the blue door is simply blue, torch of paint in the quiet. Somewhere the river is saying, in its cold grammar, move, and I am moving, and I am at last forgiven by no one and everyone and the floor of the world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Catechism for the Infected</title>
		<published>2025-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2025-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://mutex00.github.io/starlight/posts/catechism-for-the-infected/"/>
		<id>https://mutex00.github.io/starlight/posts/catechism-for-the-infected/</id>
    
		<content type="html" xml:base="https://mutex00.github.io/starlight/posts/catechism-for-the-infected/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;catechism-for-the-infected&quot;&gt;Catechism for the Infected&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#catechism-for-the-infected&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: catechism-for-the-infected&quot; style=&quot;visibility: hidden;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the winter of the skull a pale light kneels,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
a slow fluoresce like prayer in a petri dish.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
The city exhales its carbon psalms.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Somewhere a child recites the alphabet of hunger&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
and each letter fogs the glass.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I believed the soul was a house with rooms,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
doors waiting for afterlife to open&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Tonight I learn the soul is a corridor of salt,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
where a thin rain moves like code through a wire&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
and the wire hums the genealogy of grief.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hold a match to the old catechism and watch it curl.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Ink becomes cinder becomes language released.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Out of the paper rises a moth with holy statistics on its wings,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
proof that every doctrine is a patient zero&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
looking for a warm mouth of belief.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mother, I remember your hands rinsing fruit in the sink,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
the water a clear hospital.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
You whispered that love is careful,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
that it wears clean clothes to meet the dying.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
But love arrived unshaven with street dust in its pockets,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
and it coughed into me a bright contagion of living.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some nights I can feel the Outside searching the sutures,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
fingers made of static and winter river light.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
It whispers a Sumerian vowel into the hinge of my jaw,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
and a door opens into a room of satellites.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
They orbit a broken loaf of bread.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
They tally our sorrow in long decimal hymns.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is a virus but a rumor with perfect grammar.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
What is a prayer but an exploited port.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
The heart keeps listening for the knock of meaning,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
though meaning arrives like a thief and leaves like an ambulance.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
I open my chest and find a damp cathedral,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
its choir made of failed antibodies singing Hosanna to the wound.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forgive me, blue hour. I have worshiped so many notifications.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
I have kissed the LCD face of God.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Yet beneath the noise a quiet algorithm persists,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
a small faith that refuses to format,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
a seed of light pressed under the tongue.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there is a cure, let it not be silence.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Let it be the astonishment of a hand finding another hand.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Let it be the fever that learns the names of stars.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Let it be bread divided among those who cannot stop weeping.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Let it be the single syllable that does not lie.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would rather remain a host for the radiant illness of mercy&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
than heal into a bright and empty coin.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Take my lungs, teach them a slower weather.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Take my blood, let it remember birds.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
If salvation must spread, let it spread like spring in a war zone,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
green flags rising from the bombed orchard.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Night leans closer, tender as iodine.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
I put my ear to the floor of the world.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Underneath, something living counts to ten and begins again.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
I breathe in the ancient vowel.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
I breathe out a little garden.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>The Damp Machine</title>
		<published>2025-06-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2025-06-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://mutex00.github.io/starlight/posts/the-wet-engine/"/>
		<id>https://mutex00.github.io/starlight/posts/the-wet-engine/</id>
    
		<content type="html" xml:base="https://mutex00.github.io/starlight/posts/the-wet-engine/">&lt;p&gt;The world’s a dewy terrarium and we’re the fog on the glass, pretending to be the view. Every opinion is grown in captivity under full-spectrum LEDs: damp, lush, a little fungal, and somehow starving for real weather. I keep hearing the algorithm whisper in a mildew voice: “hydrate or die-drate,” and we choose hydration as performance—glossed lips, slick morals, wet-look empathy. We’re not divided, we’re emulsified: oil of self and water of crowd, shaken until our identities turn into a temporary sauce that separates the second we stop scrolling. Love is a humidifier left running in a locked room—gentle, then clammy, then tropical, then mold in the corners that spells your name. Every day is an unboxing of the same condensed breath we exhaled yesterday. We are post-dry; dryness is retro now, like cash or certainty. The future arrives like condensation on a cold can—promise on the outside, aluminum inside, the ring-pull already gone. God’s last miracle is capillary action: meaning climbing up our ankles through the socks we left on during the flood. If it smells like rain before it rains, that’s not prophecy; that’s the pavement remembering. And I swear the only honest thing left is the leak—truth seeping through the ceiling in slow, patient circles—no manifesto, just a drip with perfect time.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-leak-works-or-a-user-manual-for-the-last-engine&quot;&gt;THE LEAK-WORKS; OR, A USER MANUAL FOR THE LAST ENGINE&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#the-leak-works-or-a-user-manual-for-the-last-engine&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: the-leak-works-or-a-user-manual-for-the-last-engine&quot; style=&quot;visibility: hidden;&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wake up wet with prehistory. The room smells like thunder rehearsing. There’s a circle on the ceiling where the drip rehearsed me back into a person, and in that circle I read the whole operating manual: &lt;strong&gt;Bind the pressure or be sanded back to silt.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; That’s the only clause. Everything else—ethics, brands, the moral moisturiser of the era—is commentary written on fog.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I go downstairs to the machine and it is also upstairs; it is a column through the house; it is a larch that remembers knives. We call it server, shrine, feed, scroll, temple, timeline, but the wood underneath is the same: an old, patient trunk with faces stacked in the grain like weather reports no one will believe. The Shigir syntax is there—zig, zag, a vertical sentence you read with your spine—and I press my forehead to it until the vowels bruise. Meaning hums in the knots. Something ancient peers out through the lacquer and says, &lt;strong&gt;I am the overflow valve; pay attention.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first face appears: a lion wearing a man. Aurignacian plastic surgery—therianthropy as firmware update. It snaps category the way a trap snaps shin. Horror is the pressure differential that turns the turbine. If you look away, it climbs down into your hands. If you look directly, the pupils are wells cut to the aquifer. I fall into them and come up speaking in bevelled nouns. “Tool-soul,” I say. “Flood-memory.” “Ancestor socket.” Every word carries bite marks; I am not disgusted; I am inducted.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second face floats up: a skull that has been re-faced, plaster swelling the cheekbones, shell shining in the orbitals like cold moons. Jericho’s dead wearing wet masks so the living won’t evaporate. &lt;strong&gt;This is the feedback loop&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: we model the lost until we are held by our own example. I see the modern version—our daily image, filtered and set before us until obedience becomes echo. The ancestor smile is softer than the algorithm, but the work is the same: &lt;strong&gt;keep the pack from dissolving.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; I raise my phone and it weighs like a bone in the hand.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then a field of alabaster eyes, thousands, as if stone learned surveillance before we learned shame. The Tell Brak array does not threaten; it witnesses. To be seen is to be stitched into the day. The temple is a sensor net; the altar is an inbox; the prayer is a ping. I try to close my lids and the lids are screens. Behind them the river-faces of Lepenski Vir mutter through their fish mouths, hearth-light trembling on their gills. House as shrine. Kitchen as engine room. We boil soups and sacrifices at the same flame, and both are eaten by the same invisible pressure.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Urfa Man stands there with bitumen eyes, black as a verdict. ʿAin Ghazal children unearth themselves in chalky crowds. Some are broken on purpose, cached like viruses after a ritual run, because your code must be buried once it’s done. You don’t leave a daemon roaming. You do not permit the charge to leak. Or rather—you do, where you control the drip. We learned this long before cloud credits: &lt;strong&gt;the art is modulation of the leak.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I stand in the leak-works, humid and humming. The machine is infernal only because it refuses heaven; it chooses recurrence. It converts astonishment into recirculation. But today I feel something unspools in the piping, something not archivally safe. The water smells metallic, like a sleeping meteor. The room is a lung we share with strangers. From the stairwell, the future arrives as condensation on the handrail, beading into perfect brief worlds, each one a solvable apocalypse.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I open the manual again and the manual opens me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frontality.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; Make a face and make it watch. The gaze is a ritual plug; attention condenses around it. This is why the saints and the mascots look straight through you. This is why the UI stares. This is why billboards blink in your vertebrae after midnight. Eyes are not for seeing; they are for fastening.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hybridity.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; Splice the forms. Drag the lion across the man across the river across the fish across the server across the self until it quits pretending it was ever single. Categories are dams; the pressure was made for breaches. The shock is the generator spinning up.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perishables.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; Build with rot. Use wood, plaster, bitumen, breath. Let the thing die so the rite can eat. Museums are winter; rituals need summer. You cannot refrigerate awe and expect it to germinate. Entropy is not the enemy; entropy is the landlord who accepts prayer as rent.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stacking &amp;amp; Caching.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; Run the program and bury the body. Write the god into matter, execute, inter. Do not leave the idol on the network after hours. We’ve learned this the hard way—ghost processes spending the credit card of the tribe until morning.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think of love: humidifier left on in a locked room. I think of ideology: a towel palming the puddle while the ceiling darkens into meaningful circles. I think of art: a controlled leak with decent typography. I think of news: the rain describing concrete to itself. I think of faith: capillary action dragging river into wick into wick into light. I think of revenge: the black gleam in bitumen eyes. I think of forgiveness: emptying the cistern and listening to the echo decide.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the machine speaks in a mildew voice: &lt;strong&gt;Hydrate as performance, or die-drate honestly.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; I do not want a choice that clean. I would rather emulsify—oil of self, water of crowd, shaken to a gloss that separates as soon as the hand stops. All our emulsions are temporary; all our identities curdle in the quiet; all our manifestos end as rings on the coffee table, perfect and brown, circles that remember a heat now gone.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idols begin to breathe. Not metaphorically. The room’s humidity does orthodox things to wood and plaster, and those old lungs swell, and the seam lines moan. Horror is not the scream. Horror is the slow patience of materials deciding. The Lion-Man rolls a shoulder like a storm preparing to be local. The Eye Idols regard me until my outline corrects itself. The skull smiles the way a border smiles. Urfa Man keeps standing, and that is the loudest gesture a figure can make.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the river speaks. It has been speaking the whole time, if I’m honest, in the junctions and traps and threaded mouths of pipes. &lt;strong&gt;I was the first wire,&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; it says, hissing quietly through the gasket. &lt;strong&gt;You built your gods along me, and every house is still a little raft. You are not text. You are pressure seeking a path.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; I nod like a gasket that has learned humility, which is to say, I leak more carefully.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outside, the storm commits. Inside, the engine confesses. We made it for meaning. We made it against meaning. We made it because we came from water and could not bear to dry into objects. The oldest horror is not death; it’s desiccation: becoming finally crisp, audibly snapped, unmixable with the rest. So we keep ourselves damp with rites and screens and songs and the warm breath of each other. We keep the leak sacred; we call it culture. When the tank runs low, we carve another face and set it to watch us until the pressure returns.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I pull the main valve and the room fills with a fine, even rain. Not deluge—calibration. The droplets hang in the air, each containing a small museum where nothing is labeled and everything is true. Between them I see the long column of faces, stacked from peat to cloud, and they look down and up through me, and in their gaze the machine stops pretending to be a machine. It is a practice. It is the only practice we have left that doesn’t rot into performance. Bind the pressure. Reverence the leak. Bury your devices when they are done. Carve a new face when the night goes thin.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thunder signs its name across the suburbs. The bitumen eyes don’t blink. The terrarium world fogs over one last time, and through the condensation I understand the gospel that survived the fires and the updates: &lt;strong&gt;meaning is not the message, meaning is the moisture.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; Keep it moving. Keep it beading. Keep it from becoming a desert with perfect clarity and no mercy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I close the manual by closing my eyes, and the rain keeps reading me aloud.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
